<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>weeknotes on </title>
    <link>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/tags/weeknotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in weeknotes on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.eoinhurrell.com/tags/weeknotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes - Week 4 - 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/weeknotes_week_4_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/weeknotes_week_4_2023/</guid>
      <description>Watching Mages and Murderdads - Planescape Torment
A fun show, pointing out as they begin Planescape Torment how much it and its setting owe to the work of Gene Wolfe, specifically The Book of The New Sun, but I think Latro in the Mist would be another apt touchstone.
Reading Predictions Scorecard, 2023 January 01
Rodney Brooks continues to bring sobering facts to much-hyped discussion.
The Dangers of Over-Engineering
Thinking a lot about simplification and connecting engineering priorities and business priorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes - Week 3 - 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/weeknotes_week_3_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/weeknotes_week_3_2023/</guid>
      <description>The Iliad I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to The Iliad, specifically the Penguin Classics Rieu translation. Excellent stuff, all the tropes of action films, embedded deep at the start of the Greek tradition. Brings back memories of classical studies in secondary school.
I listened to Elizabeth Vandiver&amp;rsquo;s The Iliad of Homer course from The Great Courses, which was short and excellent.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Architecture diagrams should be code
Discoverable docs are a problem with as many answers as there are people thinking about it, this one seems good if you&amp;rsquo;re not already committed to other tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes - Week 1 - 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/weeknotes_week_1_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/weeknotes_week_1_2023/</guid>
      <description>Beginning with work year with a hackathon An excuse to further my Rust learning, and work with a couple of engineers who know more than me on the topic, I learned a lot. Types provide so much, it would be unwise to forget their power and place (felt rusty after years away!)
Some links I found helpful:
https://github.com/rochacbruno/py2rs https://google.github.io/comprehensive-rust/ into_rust(): screencasts for learning Rust Commentary:
Thoughts on Rust After Six Months Rust for Data Engineering—what&amp;rsquo;s the Hype About?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
