<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes - Week 2 - 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/weeknotes_week_2_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/weeknotes_week_2_2023/</guid>
      <description>Swrve got acquired Per MessageGears Acquires Mobile Marketing Leader Swrve Great news for all involved, happy for the team.
Finished Spinoza&amp;rsquo;s Ethics Fantastically interesting book, a lot to digest.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Data Systems Tend Towards Production Bytesize Architecture Sessions Design Docs, Markdown, and Git Logging Practices I Follow Pip Install Data_team &amp;gt; A lot of technical reading this week
The Power of Journaling Writing and Labelling in a Journal Writing Docs Well: Why Should a Software Engineer Care?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Data Product to Search People in Your Network</title>
      <link>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/building_a_data_product_to_search_people_in_your_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/building_a_data_product_to_search_people_in_your_network/</guid>
      <description>The below was originally written for and published on the Cohort company blog, Oct 6, 2017.
Dr. Eoin Hurrell leads Data at Cohort. Here, he reflects on what’s involved in designing a system to ingest and analyze massive volumes of public data, to make predictions on relationships, and things people are knowledgable on.
Cohort helps you find the people you need, through the people you already know and trust. It sounds simple, but the experience of existing social search is much closer to “I am looking to follow/connect with a person on this site”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Books I Read in 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/top_books_i_read_in_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/top_books_i_read_in_2022/</guid>
      <description> Non-Fiction Ethics by Baruch de Spinoza The Staff Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Path by Tanya Reilly Fiction Peace by Gene Wolfe The Heart of a Dog by Mikhail Bulgakov The Wasp Factory by Iain Banks The Romance of the Three Kingdoms Mason &amp;amp; Dixon by Thomas Pynchon Last Days by Brian Evenson Pattern Recognition by William Gibson The Sailor Who Fell from Grace with the Sea by Yukio Mishima The Secret History by Donna Tartt Dune by Frank Herbert </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes - Week 1 - 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/weeknotes_week_1_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eoinhurrell.com/posts/weeknotes_week_1_2023/</guid>
      <description>Beginning with work year with a hackathon An excuse to further my Rust learning, and work with a couple of engineers who know more than me on the topic, I learned a lot. Types provide so much, it would be unwise to forget their power and place (felt rusty after years away!)
Some links I found helpful:
https://github.com/rochacbruno/py2rs https://google.github.io/comprehensive-rust/ into_rust(): screencasts for learning Rust Commentary:
Thoughts on Rust After Six Months Rust for Data Engineering—what&amp;rsquo;s the Hype About?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
